# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, this is Wang Gang.
# 本期视频和大家分享一道自贡名菜
In this video, I will share a ZiGong recipe with you:
# 仔姜鲜锅兔
Zijiang Xianguo Tu
("Stir-fried rabbit with young ginger")
# 首先我们准备新鲜宰杀的肉兔一只
First, we need a freshly-butchered rabbit.
# 把肝脏取下之后清洗干净备用
We need to remove the liver and rinse it thoroughly.
# 四川的兔肉摊主会将兔头和兔皮留下来回收利用
Butchers in Sichuan will typically remove the rabbit head and skin for further uses.
# 所以只会留下肝脏和兔腰给消费者
Therefore, they only leave rabbit liver and kidneys for their customers.
# 清洗的过程中必须将腹部多余的肥油去除
We have to clean up the excess fat inside the rabbit's belly.
# 然后将兔肉剁成1厘米左右的小方块备用
Then, we cut the rabbit into 1cm cubes.
# 剁好之后下一步开始腌制
After that, we start marinating.
# 盆中加入食用盐1大勺（约3克）
Add a spoon of salt (about 3g).
# 加入胡椒粉1勺（约1克）
A spoon of ground white pepper (about 1g).
# 加入适量的料酒
And some Chinese cooking wine
# 然后朝着一个方向搅拌至粘手为止
Then, we mix it up in one direction until it gets sticky.
# 中途加入1小把干淀粉拌匀
Add a handful of starch.
# 最后加入植物油10克拌匀
Finally, we add in 10g of vegetable oil.
# 这一步的目的是防止兔肉下锅粘连
Adding oil can prevent the rabbit from sticking when cooking.
# 拌匀之后下一步开始准备辅料
Now, let's prepare some minor ingredients.
# 准备生姜和大蒜各20克拍散之后剁碎备用
Crush and mice 20g of fresh ginger and garlic each.
# 准备小米辣50克切碎备用
Mince 50g "Xiaomila" chili pepper.
# 小米辣最好可以切碎一些这样更加的入味
We can mince the chill pepper as fine as possible so it will have better flavor penetration.
# 准备仔姜60克切成姜丝备用
Next, we shred 60g of young ginger.
# 准备二荆条5个切成小粒备用
We cut 5 "Erjingtiao" chili peppers into cubes.
# 下一步开始制作
Now, let's start cooking.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
We need to heat up the wok first.
# 锅烧热之后加入宽油
Then, we add Kuan You (literally "broad oil").
# 油温烧至4成热之后将腌制好的兔丁下锅滑熟
After the oil heat up to about 120°C, add in the rabbits.
# 待兔丁定型之后再用炒勺轻轻推散
After the shape of rabbit gets fixed, we push the wok spoon against the rabbit tenderly to distribute it.
# 过早搅动会导致兔肉脱浆
Pushing too early will lead to the cornstarch on the rabbit falling apart.
# 将兔肉滑至7成熟之后倒出控油备用
We take out the rabbit after it's 70% cooked.
# 然后锅中加入菜籽油150克烧至6成热
Add 150g of rapeseed oil into the wok and heat it up to about 180°C.
# 油温6成热之后加入一小把青花椒
Add in a handful of Sichuan green peppercorns.
# 然后再加入剁好的姜蒜末下锅爆香
Then, add in the minced ginger and garlic. Stir fry until aromatic.
# 姜蒜末爆香之后加入一半小米辣碎
After that, add in half of the minced "Xiaomila" chili pepper.
# 加入红油豆瓣酱15克小火炒香爆出红油
Add in 15g chilli oil doubanjiang. Stir fry until the red oil (chilli and spice infused vegetable oil) starts to effuse.
# 豆瓣酱炒香之后加入一半仔姜丝
Add in half of the young ginger shreds.
# 翻炒均匀之后将滑好的兔丁下锅
After mixing together those ingredients, we can add in the rabbit.
# 然后加入适量的清水
Add in some water.
# 清水的量没过兔丁一半就行
The amount of water should be half-way over the rabbit.
# 开中小火烧3分钟之后开始调味
Turn down the stove to medium-low, boil for 3 min and we can start seasoning.
# 3分钟之后开始调味
After 3 min, we start seasoning.
# 锅中加入食用盐1小勺（约2克）
Add in a small spoon of salt (about 2g),
# 加入胡椒粉1小勺
a small spoon of ground white pepper,
# 加入少许白糖提鲜
a little bit of sugar to enhance the umami taste,
# 加入生抽酱油3克
and 3g of light soy sauce.
# 调好味之后加入剩余的辣椒和仔姜丝
After seasoning, we add in rest of the chili and ginger slices.
# 翻炒均匀之后即可出锅装盘
After mixing together all the ingredients, we are ready to serve.
# 一道鲜辣十足的自贡名菜就制作完成
A spicy and delicious Zigong dish is finished.
# 下面开始技术总结
Now, let's get to the technical summary.
# 第一，最好选择现宰杀的兔肉，这样的肉感才能做到最佳
First, we should use freshly-butchered rabbit, so that we will get the best texture of the meat.
# 第二，腌制的时候干淀粉不能太多否则下锅容易脱浆
Second, we can't add too much starch when marinating, otherwise it will fall apart from the meat when cooking.
# 第三，此菜为鲜辣仔姜味突出，不可加泡椒
Third, the dominant flavor of this dish comes from the young ginger, and therefore we can't add any pickled chili.
# 鲜锅兔的技术总结完毕
That is the technical summary of this dish.